# **Bernard Charles Cicchetti**

2022B Mather Way Elkins Park, PA 19027 (267) 693-2797 (C) bclal24@hotmail.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

Dedicated educator with ten years of teaching experience seeking a position as a Health and Physical Education instructor. Maintains a passion for instilling in children the importance of lifelong learning, health, and fitness. Serves as a role model through extensive participation in fitness activities and coaching of competitive basketball and noncompetitive activities with a focus on team sportsmanship, physical strength, endurance, and flexibility.

## **CERTIFICATION**

Pennsylvania State Certification: K-12 Teacher of Health/Physical Education, 05/2003 New Jersey State Standard Certification: K-12 Teacher of Health/Physical Education, 11/2006

### PROFESSIONAL TEACHING EXPERIENCE

K-12 Health/Physical Education Teacher- 2007-2016

# Philadelphia City Schools-Philadelphia, PA

- Taught Health/Physical Education classes to students in grades K-12
- Coach all athletic teams the school has to offer (West Oak Lane Charter)
- Participated in first year of a Renaissance/turn-around school improvement program in 2010-2011 (Young Scholars: Frederick Douglass Charter School)
- Made AYP in second year of five year improvement plan for 2011-2012 academic year
- From 2007-2010, taught Physical Education classes and coached high school basketball without the use of a gymnasium (Maritime Academy Charter High School)

Middle School Health/Physical Education Teacher- 2004-2007

### Camden's Promise Charter School-Camden, NJ

- Taught Health/Physical Education classes to students in grades 5-8
- Started a soccer after-school program
- Started a flag football after-school program

#### **RELATED EXPERIENCE**

Teacher/Coach of Youth Soccer- 2016-present **I9Sports-Montgomery County, PA** 

# K-12 Daily Substitute Teacher- 2012-2013 Lancaster County Public Schools-Lancaster County, PA

High School Boys Varsity Head Basketball Coach-Maritime Academy Charter High School-Philadelphia, PA 2007-2010

Middle School Boys Head Basketball Coach-Camden's Promise Charter School-Camden, NJ 2005-2007

### **Relevant Accomplishments**

- Earned program's first ever varsity victory on December 10, 2007
- Registered first winning record in school history in 2009-2010
- Earned the program's first ever winning record in 2006-2007
- Went to the playoffs for the very first time in 2007
- Awarded 2<sup>nd</sup> place in the Camden City Basketball League for the 2006-2007 season on March 13, 2007
- Won first place in the middle school boys' 4 x 100 meter relay race at the 2015 Penn Relays Carnival

### **EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Seven (7) Pennsylvania Approved Continuing Education Credits:

Go towards a Graduate Degree in Education and PA Level II Teaching Certification.

# <u>Bachelor of Science Degree: Health and Physical Education- 2002</u> Marywood University, Scranton, PA

- Cum Laude Graduate
- <u>Collegiate Activities:</u> <u>Varsity Basketball</u>: 1997-1999; <u>Varsity Soccer</u>: 1999-2000; <u>Health/Phys. Ed. Major's Club</u>: 1997-2001.

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Assistant Basketball Coach-2012-2013, Ephrata High School

• Assistant coach for high school varsity and junior varsity girls' team.

**Basketball Coach**-2010, Camden Academy Charter High School

• Coached during the 2010 South Jersey Boys Fall Basketball League.

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.